Hello guys and welcome back. So now in this video what we're going to do is do all of the coding
right. So the first script which we will be making is for the objective manager or right.
So I'm just going to name this as objective manager. All right. Then the next script will be
objective trader. Then after this the final script will be the zombie spawner. Right now
let's open this up and visual studio code or whatever texture you are using. So I'm going to open
both of the objective scripts and then the zombie spawner right. Now from the objective manager
we will start. So let me first of all delete the start and update method and then on the top.
I'm going to add these two packages. The first one is for the UI and the second one is
system dot collections. All right. And then right at the top in square baggels type system dot
serializable and then right down below I'm going to create a class by the name of objective
all right. And then in this objective class what we're going to do is we're going to create a
public string by the name of objective name. And then reference to a command check
which will be the objective reader. All right. After this we're going to create a public
objective type array and name it as objectives. All right then we need a reference to the text
and the text will be the objective name text. All right. So just name this as objective name
text. Okay. Then it will public came object and this will be to our objective UI.
Okay. Or you can say the objective panel. Then we will create an integer by the name of current
objective index. It will be zero and this will keep track of which objective is currently
active. Okay. And also we want to save that in the
directory that whatever objective is completed and if the player died then of course when we
respawn the player or you can see when we restart the game we want the current objective to be
the last one which we save. All right. So in order to save the objective we will create a
private const spring name it as save underscore key and that will be equals to current objective.
All right. Then create a bull. Name this as is showing
text and set it default. I mean by default set it to false so that we don't show the objective
text by default or it. Then create a private coroutine name it has show
that's it. Now let's make a method in which when we press the type key we want to show the
objective. Okay. The current objective whatever the current objective is. So in order to do that
let's create an enumerator type method. Name this as show objective for seconds. This will take
a float as a parameter and name it as time then. In here we will show the objective but let's
first fall make one more method which is by the name of a date objective UI. This will take
bool as a parameter by name of hide instance. Okay. In this we will first fall check that if the
current objective index is less than the objective dot length. All right. What is if condition
means if that there are still objective left then what we want to do. We want to show name
of that current objective. Okay. So in order to show the name we make the objective name dot text
equals to the objectives then we take the current objective index and then we take its name.
All right. Else in the else we show or you can say we otherwise display that all objectives are
done. Okay. So that's why I've typed right here all objectives complete. All right then right here
if we want UI hidden instantly okay. So if the hide instance is true it means to hide the objective
text we hide it and if it is false then it means to show it. So then right here we select true in
order to show the objective UI okay. Now if we get back our tail in which we show the objective
for a few seconds in here we will first of all show the UI panel by calling the update update
objective UI method and pass false to it then we will certainly showing text to true what this
will do is mark text as visible. Then right here we need to wait for the current second so
the given second is time and time will come from this parameter to this so if it is 3 or 4 or 5
right and then right here in this line we hide the UI after time expires and then we mark text as
hidden right there. Okay. So this was for showing the objective UI now in order to show the objective
UI using the tab button right here above the show objective for second method we will create
this update method in which we say that if the tab button is pressed and we check if quarantine
is already running if it is running we will stop it and then right here we start quarantine that
shows objective UI for five seconds. So now this five seconds will pass to this and it will show
the objective text for five seconds and then it will disable it. All right.
Now when an objective is completed and we want to update the text and also the objective
okay in order to do that and also we want to save that as well so whatever objectives
completed we want to save it so if the player dies then that objective still mark as completed.
So now to do that let's scroll down and write at the end make a method by the name of update
objective triggers in which okay in this method right here we activate only the trigger of the
current objective okay so first of all right here in this for each loop what we do is we disable
all triggers first okay when the game start we disable all of them then we only enable
trigger of the current objective okay so for example if none of the objective is true
then we first of all disable all of the triggers then enable only the first objective
triggers all right now if the first objective is done of course we want to save that so in order
to save that what we're going to do is appear right after the show objective for second
we will create one more method by name of complete objective this will be called when an object
is complete and in this first of all we move to the next objective all right whenever an object
is object is computed we'll move to the next one then right here we save the progress in player
prefs okay in player prefs we save the current objective index we save it player prep.save
then right here we update UI but we hide it okay and then right here we switch trigger for
the next objective all right now for example if the player dies then of course when the new
game starts we want to load the data back again okay we want to load the data but if there is
doesn't exist any data then we start the game from the beginning okay so make a load progress
method which right here we defaulted to 0 if there is no save data available okay if save data
is available then we load that else we just simply start the game from the beginning
okay this is all what we are doing in the objective manager script okay now at the top right
here let's add a start method and in the start method let's call the load progress first of all
then the update objective UI to which we will pass through and then the update objective triggers
that is it now let's move to the objective trigger in this script we will attach the script
to our trader so whenever the player collards will it it will either complete the objective
all right or complete the whole game I mean it will it will be basically use for completing
each of the objective okay and it will also give track of which objective triggered this is
okay so in order to do all of that stuff first of all we need a reference to the objective
trigger script I mean the objective manager script and I'm going to name this as manager
then let's create a on trigger enter method right here in which we will check that
if whatever that is triggered with this objective trigger came objective it's tag is not player
then we simply return and don't do anything but if it is the player then we want to complete
the objectives we will call the objective manager script right here which we name as just manager
so manager and then we will call the complete objective right there and then what we're going to do
is we're going to disable this objective trigger so that it doesn't do anything else then so
just type came object or directive for us now the last thing which we need to add in the objective
manager is for example for now we will be testing these objectives to see if it works or not
and it will store the data in the player prefs okay but now we need to make one more method
in which we delete this player prefs data okay because once the game is all completed with
the whole story or you can see the whole objective then of course we want this testing data which
is safe to be deleted okay so for that purpose right here at the bottom let's make one more
method by the name of reset objectives in this first of all we use the delete key of the player
prefs which will remove only the save objectives okay then we will save that and then we set the
current objective index to zero we hide the UI immediately and then we enable trigger for first
objective right and then we just for testing we show that objective progress reset now using a key
we will be resetting the objectives so for that right here in the update right after this
if condition we will add one more if condition which we say that if the peak is pressed we will
reset the objectives all right now save this get back right here and let's click on the environment
to actually let's click on player related and on the inside the player related we have the game
manager to the game manager drag and drop the objective manager script and now in here we will
be adding the objectives but first of all let's assign these values so for the objective UI we
will try and drop that and then for the objective name text we will try and drop that now our first
objective will allow let's set up the story let me change to a 3D mode and let's double click on
our character right there okay so our first objective will be to find this spester and then we
will add its own wizard hearing by using the pistol the player will kill their zombies okay so
the first objective will be to guide the player to find the spester right here okay so if you click
on this game manager right here click on plus sign open this up okay in the objective name
should be the same as we type right here so I'm just gonna copy that click on game manager and
then paste it right here okay so this will be our first objective which is find something for protection
from zombies and now when we find something for protection from zombies we for example if we find
this pistol then we will pass this objective okay so that's why now we need to add this objective
trigger by using which this objective will be completed okay so what I'm gonna do right here is
I'm gonna select this spester and for this spester I'm gonna create a empty game object
okay and then move this game object outside now this object is in the same spot as that
okay let's change its rotation and then to this there are box collider okay there it is so now
in the player collides with this game make sure it is a stringer and also to this object the
objective trigger is added and for the manager drag and drop the manager script which is attached
to the game manager okay make sure it is a stringer and this is added and now in the player
collides with this box collider okay then the player will find this pistol right here and the
objective will be completed because now the player has something for protection from these zombies
okay so I'm just gonna name this as oh one or objective one
all right we now need to move and create one more objective okay so now the player has
pistol shoot all these zombies right here move forward for example right here
there will be a few zombies now right here as well we're gonna add one more rifle right here okay
actually let's now undo it here the player will get inside this house let me select it and let's
rotate it like that so let's do is fully open okay and in here somewhere we will add the second
objective but I think the video is a bit lengthy so we're just gonna end this video right here
and continue from the next one.